# Amit Khivesara

Khivi



# Summary

Programmer and Technical leader with 20 years of experience of leading enginering and data science teams to build customer focussed solutions. I have been instrumental in transforming engineering teams to the next stage. Over the years I have build strong technical cultures within organizations. Based on my experience as a technical leader I authored a book on process, people and companies.

# Philosophy

Embrace Change	Change is inevitable	Be Lazy	Do more with less
Open Intent	Share before, not after	Roughly Right	Perfection is a myth
Be Inquisitive	Listen, Learn, Contribute	Feedback	Improve deployments
Outsource	Make oneself redundant	Measure Failure	Success travels easily

# — Management Skills

Communications	Open	Productivity	Extreme Programming
Mentor	Individuals	Process	Continuous Learning
Manage	Global Teams	Technical	High-Quality

## Computer Skills

Recent	Scala, Python, C/C++	Past	Java, Objective-C
Dabble	Golang, JavaScript	Technologies	Databases, Machine Learning,
Passable	PHP, Ruby	Platforms	Data Pipelines, Cloud

## Experience

2020-Present	Technical Advisor, Innovision Imaging.
2019–Present	Technical Advisor, needl.ai.
2016–Present	Technical Advisor, Verne Global.
2016–Present	Technical Advisor, Netcore.

## 2019–2020 Senior Director, AI Engineering, Target.

Leading the AI team for supply-chain and forecasting

- Leading global team responsible for AI strategies for Supply Chain & Demand Forecasting
- o Transformed research culture to be business focussed

#### 2017–2019 Director, Engineering, Target.

Leading the data science team for e-commerce search

Technologies: Docker, Kubernetes, C, Python, Ansible

- o Managed the engineering and data-science team for e-commerce search
- o Integrated a AI deep learning model to enable target.com search
- o Built a continous delivery culture

#### 2016–2017 **Head of Engineering**, Emissary.io, New York City, NY.

Emissary is a platform connecting sales professionals with former executives who have specific knowledge about their important sales targets.

Technologies: Google App Engine, Python, Bash

- Transformed processes to an agile development methodology
- Hardened security practises
- Developed a testing culture

#### 2014–2016 **Head of Engineering**, Betterpath, New York City, NY.

Betterpath is a data driven health care startup focused on improving care for patients. I lead the engineering team.

Technologies: Scala, Bash, Datomic, Ansible

- o Built and managed the engineering team
- o Setup outsourced QA team in Ukraine
- Obesigned and built reliable infrastructure

## 2012–2013 Senior Software Engineer, Konnect2, Madison, NJ.

Konnect2 is a financial services firm specializing in providing structured data exchange and algorithms for the global bond market. As one of the company's first employees, I took the product from an idea to deployment.

Technologies: Amazon Web Services, Scala, Postgres, Ansible

- Built feed handlers for bond trading market streams
- Scaled infrastructure
- Designed and implemented deployment pipelines

## 2008–2012 **CTO**, Mesh Capital, Jersey City, NJ.

Mesh Capital is a quantitative trading firm specializing in high-frequency trading. As the company's first employee I wrote the initial software that traded propriety capital

Technologies: Linux, Java, Ruby

- o Built and managed the high-caliber engineering team
- Primary responsible for execution and delivery of trading strategy to Canadian Markets
- Responsible to execution and delivery of strategic initiatives

2005–2008 Technical Lead, Roundbox, Florham Park, NJ.

Roundbox developed infrastructure to support mobile broadcast environments. I lead the global engineering team responsible for our server offerings.

Technologies: Linux, C++, Perl

- o Leading a distributed global team
- Build the world's only solution to support multiple broadcast standards (US and Europe) .
- o Contributor to industry standards to interoperate with large vendors

#### 2002–2005 Senior Software Engineering, Xebeo Communications, Iselin, NJ.

Xebeo was a successful company that built a high-speed carrier-grade MPLS router. UTStarcom bought Xebeo in May, 2003. I was leader within the software team and build and managed the network platform.

Technologies: FreeBSD, C, Python, Bash

- o Primary engineering lead on platform
- Architected the configuration and system datastore
- o Responsible for the test automation framework

#### 1996–2002 Member of Technical Staff, Bell Labs, Lucent Technologies, Murray Hill, NJ.

DataBlitz is a high-performance, ACID, main-memory database system. I lead the team from a research prototype to worldwide deployment by Lucent within its flagship telecommunication products.

Technologies: Solaris, C++, Tcl, Ksh

- o Deliver solutions with 5 nines reliability
- o Built database system 10 times read performance than any commercial database
- o Lead the team during organisation change to continue to deliver

## Education

1994–1996 MTech, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India.

Masters in Computer Science and Engineering

1990–1994 BTech, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India.

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering

#### Awards and Achievements

2019 Awarded, Target, Minneapolis, MN.

Chief Data Officer Award

1999 Awarded, Bell Labs, Murray Hill, NJ.

Bell Labs President's Silver Award

1994 Academic Distinction, GATE, 1994.

All India Rank 9

1990 Academic Distinction, IIT JEE, 1990.

All India Rank 28

# Publications

2015 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Companies.

Book available at http://a.co/iluqz2A

2020 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Software.

To be published

## Interests

Privacy Technology and Society

Travel Small town America Film Documentaries Music The Doors

Enjoy Bourbon

Food Korean